天啊 我们本该从教会中消除偶像崇拜与迷信
How in God's name, we suppose to bannish by adultery.
废除宗教仪式
and superstition and empty ritual from our churches.
却不期然它们依旧在宫内大行其道
when they are still practice here at court.
何时我可觐见陛下 大人
When shall I meet the Majesty, my lord?
很快 陛下也热切期待与你会谈
very soon. Majesty is most eager to talk to you.
同时他鼓励您书写一份详尽供述
In the meantime, he encouraged you to write a lengthy declaration of.
来细述叛乱之缘由 及你的所作所为
everything you did during the rebellion and the reasons for it.
别动
Keep still.
你是谁 来此作甚
who are you? what are you doing here.
你不能来此
You can't be here.
天哪 居然真是这样 我真不敢相信
Oh my God, it's true. I didn't believe it.
出去 出去
get out. get out.
不行 她是我的未婚妻
no. she is my fiancee.
- 请允许我… - 不 我不…
- Well, should I…? - No, I don't…
不许来这里
There's no cause being here.
我警告过你
I warned you.
他还活着么
Is he alive?
荷尔拜因大师求见
Master Holbein.
- 荷尔拜因大师 - 参见陛下
- Master Holbein. - Your Majesty.
我得请求陛下宽恕
I must beg Your Majesty's pardon.
宽恕？所为何事？
Pardon? What for?
在您的宫中犯有殴打行为
I have committed an assault within the verge of your court.
殴打 你 但是你不过是个艺术家啊
An assault? you? But you're an artist.
受陛下委派 我在为米赛尔登女士画像
I was painting the picture of Lady Misseldon that Your Majesty commisioned,
但是有位绅士前来阻隔
but a gentleman interrupted us.
你做了何事
What did you do?
我把那位绅士推倒了
I threw the gentleman into some shelves.
您做的对 荷尔拜因大师
You did the right thing, Master Holbein.
我完全宽恕你 换作是我也会那么做的
And I'll forgive you freely, I might have done the same thing myself.
请去完成画作吧 我迫不及待
Just finish the portrait. I can't wait.
谢陛下
Thank you, Your Majesty.
荷尔拜因大师
Master Holbein.
罗伯特·泰维斯托克爵士求见
Sir Robert Tavistock.
- 罗伯特爵士 您看起来受到过攻击 - 陛下
- Sir Robert, you look have assaults. - Your Majesty.
我前来严正投诉荷尔拜因大师
I have a great complaints to make against Master Holbein.
我与一位女士订过婚
I am engaged to a young woman.
却发现他在给她画像 而她全身赤裸
but found him painting her. Naked.
裸体
Naked?
是的 陛下 在床上 如同荡妇一般
Yes, Your Majesty. on a bed, like some concubine.
我强烈要求陛下为其邪恶 不道德 以及对我暴力侵犯
I demanded that, Your Majesty, punish Mr. Holbein severely, for his lewdness,
严惩荷尔拜因先生
his immorality, and his violence against me.
此事不必针对荷尔拜因先生 冲我来好了
You have not to do with Mr Holbein, but with me.
我实话告诉你
I tell you frankly.
如果我有7个农夫 我可以造就7个贵族大人
If I have seven peasants, I can make seven lords.
但是我有7个贵族大人 也造就不出一个荷尔拜因
but if I have seven lords, I couldn't make one Holbein.
现在如实告诉我 你还希望我惩处荷尔拜因先生吗
Then tell me truthfully, do you still wish me to punish Mr. Holbein?
不 陛下 我请求陛下宽恕
No, Your Majesty. I ask for Your Majesty's pardon.
我是陛下的恭顺忠仆
I am Your Majesty's humble and obedient servant,
不再投诉荷尔拜因先生
and make no complaints against Mr. Holbein.
好小伙
Good lad.
圣诞快乐 罗伯特
Happy Christmas, Robert.
- 陛下 - 亲爱的
- Majesty? - Sweetheart.
我可以向您引见某人吗
May I present someone to you?
当然
Very well.
索尔兹伯里女伯爵曾是我的家教
The Countess of Salisbury was my old governess.
我知道 我很了解这位女士
I know. I know the Lady very well.
- 玛格丽特女士 - 陛下
- Lady Margaret? - Your Majesty.
非常欢迎你来宫中
You are very welcome here to court.
我知道你鲜少踏离您的华宅豪居
I know how rearly you quit your fine house.
这倒是真的
It is true.
我喜欢虔诚传统的生活方式 陛下
I prefer to live a life based on piety and traditional ways, Your Majesty.
您是宫中所有人的榜样
You're an example to everyone here at court.
你的儿子波尔红衣主教近来如何
How was your son, Reginald Pole?
他还在意大利就学吗？
Is he still studying in Italy?
的确是的 陛下
Yes, indeed, Your Majesty.
他现在帕多瓦大学
He is now at Padua Univeristy,
他对陛下不胜感激
and has more reasons than most to be grateful to Your Majesty.
因为不久之前 你还资助过他的学费
Since until very recently, you continue to pay his fees.
我曾对他非常属意
I showed great interest in him.
他是我的表亲 展现了成就学者的良好前景
He showed great promise as scholar, as well as being my cousin,
不过 在他拒绝了我册封他为有史以来最年轻的
Still, when you refused my offer to make him the youngest.
温切斯特大主教职位之际
ever Bishop of Winchester.
我记得我只好抛弃他
I remeber I had to thump him.
陛下务必相信*从红衣主教方面来说此事并无裨益
Your Majesty must believe it was not in gratitude on Reginald's part. No, no.
他在失去陛下眷顾之际着实热泪盈眶
He was in tears after leaving Your Majesty's presence.
事实上犬子相对于担任社会公职或出人头地来说
The truth is my son is too much of a scholar.
更倾向于做一位离群索居的学者
and private person ever to desire public office or notoriety.
既然如此 我原谅他了
Then after all, I forgive him.
- 陛下 - 索尔兹伯里女士
- Majesty. - Lady Salisbury.
你们两位女士在密谋什么吗
You ladies are conspiring something.
我们俩希望在此圣诞之际向您引见某人
we were both like to present someone else to Your Majesty at this Christmastide.
好吧
Very well.
陛下 这位是…
Your Majesty, this is…
我女儿伊丽莎白 不用你来告诉我
My daughter Elizabeth. You don't need to tell me.
过来吧 孩子
Come here, child.
[法语]参见陛下
Votre Majeste.
[法语]您好吗
Ca va.
[法语]我很好 小乖乖
Ca va bien, ma petite.
[法语]来这里
Veniez ici.
当心点
Attencion.
阖家欢乐
Joyeux son famille.
陛下 罗伯特·阿斯克已到
Your Majesty, Mr. Robert Aske.
- 陛下 - 阿斯克先生
- Majesty. - Mr.Aske.
来
Come.
我很高兴见到你 阿斯克先生
I am very glad to see you, Mr. Aske.
长久以来 我相信我被严重误传了
For a long time, I believed I was badly misinformed.
关于王国北部地区动乱缘由
about the causes of disturbances in the Northern part of our kingdom.
我已经阅读了你那份详尽坦诚的诉说
but I have read your full and frank explanation.
我被你们起事所诉求的公义所折服
I am persuaded by the justice of your cause.
我依然将热爱我的臣民视为王国之维
I still deem the commonwealth of the realm, and love of my subjects,
远远胜于对任何财富的渴求 阿斯克先生
Mr. Aske, far more than any riches.
陛下言语让小人担当不起
I'm truely humbled by Your Majesty's words.
在此斗胆请陛下明示
and ask in all you ability.
陛下是否将会履行沙福克公爵大人
If your sacred Majesty intends to fulfill those pledges made in Your Majesty's name,
在庞蒂弗拉克特以陛下的名义所做的诸般承诺
by his grace, the Duke of Suffolk at Pontefract.
所有的一切都会履行
In every part, the general and liberal pardon.
大赦将可延伸至所有北方臣民
shall be extended to all our Northern subjects.
将在约克郡自由选举新一届议会
There will be a free election to a Parliament to be held at York.
教士们不受我们的好恶所左右
when members of churchmen without our displeasure,
他们可以畅所欲言 直抒胸臆
shall them may speak and show their learning and their free minds.
不仅如此 在我的沙福克公爵
Futhermore, after my Lord Suffolk has come down to you.
携带王玺确定上述诸等事宜之后
with the great seal to claim on this,
为明示我们对北方臣民的挚爱
then to show the great love we bear on the Northern subjects.
我们将亲自前往约克郡
we ourselves shall come to York.
并在该地为我的王后举行加冕礼 阿斯克先生
and it is there, Mr. Aske, where my Queen shall be crowned.
陛下真是宽宏无量
Your Majesty is truely gracious.
我向您发誓 您将发现王国之内
I swear to you. You will find no more loving and loyal people.
没有比北部约克郡更爱 更忠于吾王的子民
on the whole of your realm than Northern Yorkshire.
尚有一事 你信中非议某些大臣
One more thing. You've written against some of my advisors,
质疑他们缺乏贵族血统
and protesting at their lack of noble blood.
陛下 我…
Your Majesty, I…
不必 我其实认同于你 不过切莫声张
No, I agree with you. But don't say anything.
现在 我有件礼物给你
Now, I have a gift for you.
陛下 我…
Majesty, I…
圣诞快乐 阿斯克先生
Happy Christmas, Mr. Aske.
相当愉悦
That is quite entertaining.
不过你兴许还不知道我是谁 对吗
but you don't even know who I am, do you?
我当然知道
Of course, I do.
你是爱德华·西摩的妻子
You're Edward Seymour's wife.
倘若他发现此事 或许会杀了你
If he ever discovered us, he'd probably kill you.
真的 他看起来友好
Really? Yet he seems so nice.
有点冷静 不过与人为善
Cold, perhaps but pleasant with all?
那是所有人的错觉
That's a mistake they all make.
[拉丁语]万福玛利亚 满被圣宠者 主与尔偕焉 阿门
Ave Maria, gratia plena, Dominus tecum, Amen.
阿斯克先生
Mr. Aske.
玛丽女士
Lady Mary.
很抱歉打搅了您祷告
I'm sorry to disturb your prayers.
一点也不 我一直在为您祷告
Not at all, since you are always a part of them.
我前来是为了让您放宽心 阿斯克先生
I come only to assure you, Mr. Aske.
因为我知道您是受主的差遣
For I know you are here upon God's work.
我相信国王陛下会满足你们的要求的
I trust the King's Majesty will grant you and your people all their desires.
我现在充满了希望
I have every hope now,
就像我一直都希望有一天您可以成为英格兰的女王
as I have ever hoped one day you will succeed as Queen of England,
可以更好地维护我们的信仰
for the better maintaining of our faith.
玛丽女士 你要知道
Lady, you must know,
人民有多么的爱戴你
how beloved you are to the people,
就如同昔日爱戴先慈一样 愿她的灵魂安息
as was your mother before you. God rest her soul.
希望这个信物可以让你一直记得我
Remember me by this.
但愿上帝保佑并眷顾你 阿斯克先生
May God bless and keep you, Master Aske.
父亲可好？听说他病了
How's father? They told me he has fallen ill.
我本想换个时间告诉你的 父亲去世了
I was going tell you at a better time. Father is dead.
去世了？什么时候？怎么会？
Dead? When? Why?
注意保持微笑 一周以前
Keep smiling. A week ago.
- 一周了？ - 是的 一周了
- A week? - Yes a week.
我安排了葬礼 他已风光大葬
I arrange the funeral, everything has done to honor him.
我本不想现在告诉你 我本该参加葬礼
You should have told me. I should have been there.
我也希望我有别的办法 但是现在不行
I wish I could be otherwise, but can't now,
你属于王宫 你得理解这个
your place is here, you have to understand that.
择日你可去他的陵墓祭拜
Later you could visit his mausoleum.
- 妹妹 - 我的夫人
- Sister. - My Lady.
我猜你已经告诉她父亲的噩耗了 她还好吗
I presume you have told her about her father, is she alright.
当然 她可是王后
Of course. She's the queen.
先生们 高贵与虔诚的人们
Gentlemen. Noble and worshipful man of this country.
我以上帝和圣乔治的名义起誓
I swear by the faith that I bear to God and St. George that I have not only.
我会原谅宽恕北方的子民 我的承诺不仅只是落纸盖玺
forgiven and pardoned the men of the North by writing under seal.
我的承诺同样发自肺腑
but also freely in my heart.
我很荣幸 这些带着圣乔治十字的人们
It is my honor that those men now wear the cross of St. George.
对我的赦免满怀感激
who thankfully accepted my free pardon.
并且会像起义前一样 愿意做忠实的臣民
and mean to be as loyal subjects, as they were before their solely insurrection.
我和王后 在此祝愿你们 新年快乐如意
And my queen and I, wish you all, a very happy and prosperous New Year.
我实实在在地告诉你们 国王是个和蔼可亲的君主
I tell you frankly, the King is a good and gracious lord.
他已经尽可能地满足了我们的请愿和诉求
who has granted us as far as he may, all our desires and petitions.
这是真的 我听他亲口承诺
It's true. I heard it from his own mouth.
他意欲在约克召开一届自由公正的议会
that he intends to hold a free and fair parliament in York.
并且在这里为王后加冕
and have the queen crowned there.
阿斯克先生 承诺复承诺 承诺何其多
Promises, Mr. Aske, just more promises.
不仅仅只是承诺
No, not just promises.
沙福克大人起誓 他会带着象征至高权威的国王御玺
Lord Suffolk is sworn to come here to bring both great authority,
他给了许多让我满意的答覆
the King's seal and thus he told me many comfortable answers.
我不得不说 阿斯克先生 虽然我赞同您
I have to tell you, Mr. Aske, though it agrees me to do so,
自从你出发之后
that since you have been away,
这儿谣言四起
there have been many rumors and a widespread.
大家都觉得国王和他的枢密院不可信任
mistrust of the King and his councel.
是啊 北方要重建修道院
Aye. The Northern lands are open monastery again.
这次我们自己做主
and this time we won't be betrayed.
告诉他们要相信我 约翰
Tell them to believe me, John.
告诉他们静等沙福克公爵大人
Tell them to wait for the coming of Lord Suffolk,
现在再次起义简直是孤注一掷
for another rising now risks everything.
曾几何时 为王公者金口玉言一诺千金
Robert, there was a time when nothing was more sure.
罗伯特 但如今…
than a promise of a prince, but now.
我们觉得那些承诺不过是愚弄臣民的权宜之计
we think these promises nothing but a policy to blind the people.
我们要再次起义 我们不会再轻信承诺
and when we rise again, we will trust no promises.
我简直不敢相信
I cannot believe this.
如果你们信不过国王 那能不能至少相信我？
If you will not trust the King, then will you at least trust me?
难道不是我一直以来指挥得当吗？
Have I not guided you well so far?
难道不是我确保大家都被赦免吗
Have I not secured a pardon for all of us?
但是你无法确保国王重建修道院
But have you secured the King's absolute promise to restore our monasteries?
公爵大人向我保证这些事宜
His Grace promised me that all those matters would be discussed.
都将在议会上畅所欲言的商讨
freely and openly in parliament.
我相信他 任何真诚善良的人
I trust him. He offered me as much as true and honest.
希冀君主所能做的 他都已经做到了
and good man could desire of their sovereign.
但我们没有任何保障
but we have no proof.
你们要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
进军卡莱尔
Marching on Carlisle.
约翰 我恳求你 看在上帝的份上
John, I plead with you, for the love of God, not to put this agreement.
切勿鲁莽行事 这会破坏我们达成的协议
in jeopardy by false actions and rush judgements.
他们早在你回来之前就已下定决心了 阿斯克先生
Their minds are already made up, Mr. Aske. Even before you returned.
压根就没有什么协定 只有空头承诺
There is no agreement just basically empty promises.
国王可不会听劝 我们只有兵谏
The King will not be moved by words but by actions.
我们现在所将做的事 不过是我们早就该做的
We shall do now, what we should have done before.
去召集大家
gather the man.
真希望玛丽公主能住在宫里 我很想念她
I wish that Lady Mary lived at the court. I miss her very much.
是啊 还有伊丽莎白公主
Yes, and Lady Elizabeth.
她可真是个甜美 聪明 开朗的孩子
Is she not the sweetest, cleverest, brightest child?
她们两个都不容易 尽管我自己也挺悲惨
It's not have been easy for either of them.
可和她们比起来 还是好多了
and for all my troubles I'm glad I never have theirs.
王后陛下
Your Majesty.
陛下 我不知道我是否该告诉你 但是
Madam. I do not know whether to tell you, but.
国王已经纳米塞尔登女士为情妇了
the King has taken Lady Misseldon as mistress.
他可以随心所欲 洛克福特女士
He must do as he will. It is we, Lady Rochford,
只有我们女人 才必须贞洁恭顺
must always honor and obey.
别为我招惹是非 而我已有大喜了
Donot leave trouble for me, for I have great reason to be happy.
沙福克公爵和掌玺大臣觐见
The Duke of Suffolk, and the Lord Privy Seal.
你立马动身去北部
You're going to North at once.
遵命 陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
为了建立起绝对的服从 你要起草一份誓词
In order to establish due obedience, you will allow minister an oath,
给那些约克郡和兰开夏郡的士绅大人们
to the leaders and gentlemen of Yorkshire and Lancashire.
他们要承认 他们曾做出过
They will acknowledge that they made other oath contrary.
叛君背主的誓约
to their allegiance and to the great offence of God.
他们必须弃绝那些誓约
They must utterly renounce them.
并且发誓做我们的诚实子民
and swear to be our true and faithful subjects.
他们必须承诺服从 甚至要不惜抛洒热血
They must commit themselves to obey and even to spill their blood to maintain.
遵从王法 并协助宗教特使执行任务
all our laws and to assist our church commissioners in their duties.
如果他们不发此誓言 那就不必对他们仁慈
If they will not take the oath, then there will be no clemency.
你需在抓捕这些人时保障自己安全
You will apprehend such persons where there is no danger to yourself. And they will,
然后依法处决他们
by law, be judged to suffer execution.
对于在约克召开议会之事
Your Majesty, what are your instructions.
您有何指示 陛下
regarding the setting of the parliament at York?
你可以说 议会不得不延期
You may say there has been necessary delays.
陛下 可我以名誉担保向他们做出了承诺
Your Majesty, I…I gave them my word upon my honor.
让我来提醒一下公爵大人 叛变
Let me remind Your Grace that rebellion.
就等同于自求天谴
is the heinous sin which cries out to God for punishment.
那是罪中之罪
It is the sin of the sin.
因为 如果纲常崩坏 就会引发淫乱
For wether is no right order, there is only carnal liberty,
罪恶和糜烂
sin and Babylonian disorder.
这些刁民无法无天祸乱整个王国
These wretched men have taken my whole realm without board.
犯君罔上 查尔斯
as they have taken me, Charles.
他们必须 也必将为此付出代价
They have to and will be punished for it.
我十分赞同陛下 如果可以的话 我想…
I agree with Your Majesty. If I might…
你给我住嘴 你不过是个贱民 克伦威尔先生
No you may not. You're low birth, Mr. Cromwell, deems you're unfit.
没有资格干预国王事务 你们退下吧
to meddle in the affairs of King's. You dismissed.
- 你好 查理 - 康斯特布尔首领
- Hey Charlie. - Captain Constable.
大多数人都聚齐了 你看上去精神不错
So most men start together. You're in good spirit.
是啊 很高兴您终于到达了
Aye, glad you are up for it.
很好 余下的人明天会加入我们
Good, the rest will be joining in us tomorrow.
我们将向卡莱尔进发 尽快攻击城堡
We will walk in the carlisle, we will attack the castle as soon as fast.
这是什么
what we've got here.
兔子
Rabbits.
兔子 你们打算拿兔子做什么？喂饱五千士兵？
Rabbits. So what are you going to do with that? Feed the five thousand?
天啊 查理 蹲下
Jesus! Charlie! Stay low!
冲出去 冲出去
Out, out.
好了
Alright.
给他点水喝
Give him some water.
天啊 苍天啊 发生了什么
My God, what in God's name has happened?
我们一起进发 阿斯克先生 在卡莱尔那里
We started together, Mr. Aske, near Carlisle,
准备充分 斗志昂扬
ready and eager to,
准备去进攻城堡
assault the castle.
然后 克里斯托弗·戴克爵士 和沙福克公爵大人
Then Sir Cristopher Dacre. and the Lord Suffolk,
带着人马从城堡里面冲了出来 挥矛就刺
came out of the castle with the men that brought these spears on those.
我们惨遭血腥屠戮 被俘
and afterwards, men of bloody chains and captures, scalds.
我眼睁睁看着两个小伙子被杀
I saw my two boy slayed.
我的天啊
God help us.
阁下们 我们完了
Sirs we are broken.
康斯特布尔先生怎么样了
What about Mr. Constable?
被俘了
Captured.
大人
My Lord.
可逮着他了 他们毁约了
We've got him. They broke their pledges.
- 我要觐见陛下 - 明白了 大人
- I mean to see the King. - Yes, My Lord.
我们要在北方全面施行戒严令
We shall impose martial law on whole of the North.
- 你是约翰·康斯特布尔？ - 是的
- John Constable? - Aye.
你否认你是叛乱活动的首领么？
Do you deny that you acted as a leader in captains of this rebellion?
我不否认 我引以为荣
No. I'm proud of it.
你会被押解往伦敦接受进一步审讯
You're going to be taken to London and examined further as your action's motives.
你是指刑讯吧 你答应会召开议会的
you mean tortured, you promised us a parliament,
但是你撒谎了 你背叛了我们
but you lied. you betrayed us.
你从没打算信守诺言 是不是？公爵大人？
You never meant to of everything, did you, did you, Your Grace?
这是不愿放弃叛乱并签署誓词的人的名单
Here are the names of those who refuse to announce their actions and sign the oath.
- 有多少？ - 74个 都要被处决 公爵大人
- How many? - 74, all to be executed, Your Grace.
事情都已圆满解决 公爵大人
It was all well done Your Grace.
您知道国王命令逮捕达西大人
You know that it is his Majesty's order to arrest Lord Darcy.
拉尔夫·艾列克爵士和罗伯特·阿斯克
Sir Ralph Ellerker and Robert Aske.
他们被控为叛国罪
They are to be charged on suspicion of treason.
但对他们密而不宣
but they must not know it.
大人 希望您一定要了解
Your Grace must surely know.
阿斯克先生 拉尔夫·艾列克爵士和我
that Mr.Aske Sir.Ralph and I.
都都公开坚决反对二次起义
were firmly and factly and openly against this new rising.
我们过去 而且现在依然相信
We believed and believe still in the promises.
陛下的承诺与善意
and assureties and good gracious of the King's Majesty.
事实如此 我们这里绝无反对国王的行为与想法
It is also true that nothing can be done or imagined here against the King's Majesty.
即使我无法让枢密院与您了解这点
that I cannot let the council and you know of.
我绝对相信您对国王陛下的忠诚
I am assured of your loyalty to his Majesty.
然而 国王要求你们和我同往南方
Nevertheless, the King requires you travel south.
就最近发生的事件做出解释
with me to explain this recent events.
这些事件看起来有违他的期望
which seems so contrary to his expressed hopes.
大人 如您所见
Your Grace can see with your own eyes.
我年迈体弱 经不起旅途劳乏
that I am old and sick and unfit to travel.
请允许我说句实话 公爵大人
Allow me to speak openly to Your Grace.
虽然我热爱并且完全信任国王陛下
Although I love and trust the King absolutely.
知道他会永远对我心怀仁慈 公正对待
and know that he would always treat me justly and mercifully.
但某些枢密院成员就难说了
I can not say the same for some of his councillors.
我确实害怕落入他们之手 大人
I would rather fear to fall into their hands my Lord.
我再次向您保证
Allow me to reassure you.
我将给国王和枢密院致函为你们求情
I will write a letter to both the King and council in all of your favours.
在走之前我会先给你们过目
and shall we show you before we leave.
就是说 我们必须去？
Then, we must go.
是的 这是王令
Yes, it is the King's command.
只求上帝垂怜
Then I say God has mercy on us.
上帝保佑你平安 我亲爱的丈夫
God bless you and keep you, my own dear husband.
你也要保重 亲爱的 我会没事的
And you too my darlings, but I shall be all right.
我相信公爵大人的诚信
for I trust in the honestly of His Grace.
他给我看了封信
He showed me a letter, it was written.
是为了我们写给枢密院的 全都是好话
to the council on our behalf and it was all good.
他说对我们好感依旧
He said he still charity for us and I doubt.
我认为我们不会受到任何伤害
any harm will come to us.
毕竟北方大部分地区都已平定
After all, what could be gained by when the North most now.
我们怎会获罪
be appeased and quiet.
我的女儿 不要流泪 你可是约克郡姑娘
Then our daughters don't weap. Your yorkshire lass,
约克郡姑娘都意志坚定 就像你们的好母亲
Yorkshire lass have iron in their souls just like your good mother.
我们很快就会再见的 我保证
You will see me again soon, I promise.
上帝保佑您 阿斯克先生
God bless you Mr.aske.
伙计们 出发
Man, march on.
上帝保佑您 阿斯克先生
God bless you Mr.aske.
我看你又在吃鹌鹑蛋 宝贝
I see you eating quail's eggs again sweetheat?
昨天你没吃吗
Did you not have those yesterday.
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
看来我对它们的喜欢渐增
I seemed to have developed fondness of them.
非常喜欢？
Especial fondness?
确实 非常喜欢
Well indeed.
因为某些原因 我需要鹌鹑蛋胜过一切
For some seasons, I desire quails eggs above anything else.
- 退下 - 陛下
- Leave. - Your Majesty.
我想你是怀有身孕了
I think you are with child.
是的
I am.
我的至爱
My love.
我的王后
My queen.
约翰·康斯特布尔
John Constable.
你这个作乱国王不可救药的首恶分子
you are a principal and irredeemable traitor and villian against the King's Majesty.
你在劫难逃
Nothing can save you.
上帝 宽恕保佑我
OH Lord. forgive me, oh Lord.
卫士 把他压倒在桌子上
Guards, hold him down on the table.
耶稣啊 上帝啊
Sweet jesus, God, jesus,
去死吧
Dame you to hell. …
大人 这趟长途奔波差点要了达西大人的命
…Lord Darcy Your Grace I think the journey almost broken him.
他歇息的地方已经安排妥当
His lodge is taken care of.
这是弗兰西斯·布赖恩爵士
This is Sir Francis Bryan.
- 阿斯克先生 - 弗兰西斯爵士
- Mr. Aske. - Sir Francis.
我奉命送您去伦敦塔
I have orders to commit you to the tower.
- 但是 - 这是为了你的安全着想
- but - it's for your own safety.
在那里 你会住得很舒适
You will be lodged comfortably enough.
克伦威尔先生想问你几个问题
Mr Cromwell desires to ask you a few questions.
我信任过您 公爵大人
I trusted you, Your Grace.
我起誓 我已经尽了全力 阿斯克先生
I swear, I have done my best for you, Mr. Aske.
沙福克公爵驾到 大人
The Duke of Suffolk, my Lord.
你要见我？
You asked to see me.
是的 公爵大人
Yes Your Grace.
说清楚 你想怎么样
Well explain yourself, what do you want?
我收到一些情报
I have some reports.
你总是有情报 克伦威尔
You always have reports Cromwell.
但这些非常有趣
But these are very interesting.
这些情报来自卡莱尔内部
They are reports from insides of Carlisle.
涉及对那些试图叛乱国王者的审判
where he says a judgement agaginst rebels who attempeted to threaten His Majesty.
一切都做的合法妥当
Everything was done leagally and properly.
74名叛乱者被审判并处决
74 rebels were jedgued and hanged.
问题就在这个地方
That's the problem.
我们都可确定的一点是
One point all of us agreed there were at least.
至少有4万名在野武装叛乱者
40, 000 rebles armed and in the field.
但是 大人仅判处74人有罪
and yet Your Grace found only 74 guilty.
我处决的是头目和重犯
I hanged those with the leaders and most guilty insides rebellion.
你当时在场听证过吗？
Had you actually been there to hear the evidence?
我必须诚实地告诉你 公爵大人
I must be honest with Your Grace, you had been accused of too great.
你被指控对那些
of leniency towards the rebels, towards.
不顺从的修道士们以及其他旧教支持者心慈手软
recalcitrant monks and other upholders of the old religion, it…
您是否全心全意镇压叛乱
it is disreputed whether you are in your heart and soul.
还是说您内心依然
fully engaged in struggle against the treasons, rebels or Wheather you are.
尊崇于教皇
in your heart still papist.
是谁 指控我
Who? Accused me?
陛下
His Majesty.
因此 国王陛下命令你返回北方
Consequently, his Majesty now demands your return North.
采取适当而有效的措施镇压乱党
and carry out an proper and efficient reprisals against these rebels and treators.
你要对他们施以雷霆手段
You are to make a terribly examples of them.
教会他们忠诚这种品质
And teach those parts of the virtues of loyalty.
74个远远不够
74 is an inadequate number.
公爵大人
Your Grace.
你问我事实的真相 我如实告你
Since you asked me for the truth, I will answer that in all parts of the realm.
对修道院的破坏极大伤害了王国各地人心
men's heart were most hurt by the destruction of the abbeyes.
因为他们有理由相信
Becuase they thought perhaps with a reason that.
这是对英国所有宗教寺院的毁灭
this was the first fruits, of the destruction, of their whole religion in England.
这里有一封你的信
This letter of yours.
你在1月19日安抚庞蒂弗拉克特城市长的信中写道
on the 19th of Jan., you wrote to reassure the mayor of common Pontefract.
「我必须对上帝和国王忠诚
"I should keep a clean true heart to God on the King.
成为国家利益着想的请愿者
and whatever more further to be a true petitioner for the common wealth good."
你还签了名 T 达西
You signed it.T Dacy?
我记得 但是我不解何错之有？
I remember it. But I am not sure, what is wrong with it.
你难道不承认 这更加暴露了你的错误愚昧
Can you not agree, was it rather spreading fauls foolingness.
比如 我们准备要拆除的教区教堂实际上引发了叛乱
For example, the parish churches we're going to put down which actully caused rebellion.
不 事实是修道院被查封
No, it was the fact, that the abbeys were being suppressed and burned.
此函写于在国王宣布赦免和叛乱结束之后的1月19日
It was 19th of Jan that after the King declared his Pardon and rebellion had ended.
我想国王也曾答应过建立一个自由的议会
But I understood the King had also agreed to a free paliament.
在那里臣民依然可以陈述他们伤心的诉愿
where subjests could still show their grief complains.
我的信只不过表示…
my letter was only meant to.
我来告诉你它表示着什么 我的大人
I will tell you what it meant, my Lord.
它意味着即使在吾王宽赦之后
What it meant is even after the King's gracious pardon,
你却依然叛心不改
you had not changed your traitor's heart and opinions.
你仍然执迷于设法废除
You continue to seek the annulment of laws.
那些为了国家安康而制定的法律
that make for the good of the commonwealth.
甚至你还想废黜国王
and you still wish to depose the King.
告诉我 为什么它们对你那么重要
Tell me, why… they were so important to you?
因为北方的修道院给穷人以保护
Because the abbeys in the North gave arms to poor men.
给贵族大人们以信念来侍奉上帝
and Lord belief to serve God.
此乃国土之至美之一
They were one of the beautiest of this realm.
对所有人与陌生人略无二致
to all men and strangers are alike.
照料他们的劳作服役 诉求
They took care of their servants, their tends,
以及社区等任何方都面面面俱到
and their local communities in every sort of way.
如同维护沟通的桥梁与屏障的堤坝
From maintaining bridges and seawalls.
看护少年男女纯洁的成长
To see girls and boys were brought up in virtue.
当他们长大成人 人们不但有了他们躯体的重塑空间
And when they stood, people not only has world of refreshment in their bodies,
同时也有精神上的庇护所在
but they also have a spirtual refuge.
所以你对查封修道院与王权至尊愤懑不已
So you grudge this suppression and the King's supremacy.
经过这番供述 上帝宽恕我们吧
After such confessions, Lord forgive us.
这并非是阿斯克先生 而是你
It is not Mr. Aske but you,
才是这造成这一切叛乱和灾难的源头和主因
who are the very oringal and chief cause of all this rebellion and mischief.
虽然你可设法按照你的意愿嫁祸于人
although You could probably find some ways of having all.
砍掉王国之内一些贵族的头颅来自保
the nobal men's head of the realm struck off you if you wanted.
不过我相信 哪怕只余下一个贵族
Yet I trust, there might be on left.
就还能最终砍下你的脑袋
who can still to strike off yours.
也许你会感觉惊奇的得知 阿斯克先生
Well, may it surprise you to learn, Mr. Aske,
基于特别的原因 我其实试图救你一命
there is very reason, I attempt to save you.
你已经回来两天了 虽然你不开心
You've been here for 2 days. But still you don't talk to me.
却不想和我说
Even though you are unhappy.
你怎么知道？
How'd you know?
你在半夜惊醒 喃喃自语
You wake in the night. You say things.
我说些什么？
What do I say?
敞开你的心怀吧
unburden your heart.
如果那样 相信我 一切会变的
If I do, believe me, everything will change.
我已经接到命令要回北方去实施惩处
I am commanded to return North to carry out retribution.
我得去处决更多的叛乱者
I must excute more rebels.
只是此番我必须试行「正确」程序
Only this time I'll trial "proper" process.
很多？
Many?
对 很多很多 成百上千
Yes, many. Many, hundreds, thousands,
我不得不杀死成百上千的男人 女人甚至孩子
I must kill hundreds of men, women or children.
否则我会失去吾王的宠信
or I'll lose the love of my King.
女人和孩子
Women and children?
我没有选择
I have no choice.
你当然有选择
Of course you have choice!
如果是你自己的孩子你会怎么去做？
What if they were your own children?!
我还得这样做
I will still have to do it.
国王陛下驾到
His Majesty, the King.
起来吧 阿斯克先生
Stand up, Mr. Aske.
克伦威尔先生已经向我禀报了你的供述
Mr. Cromwell has reported your words to me.
因此我特意前来和你谈谈
I've come to talk to you.
关于你极度关心的修道院以及其他宗教设施
About the abbeys and the religious houses you care so much about.
请坐
Please.
你深爱那些修道士
You have so much affection for these monks.
但我可向你证实 他们远非良善信徒
Yet I can prove to you how far they are from good religious men.
他们声称甘于贫穷 贞洁 服从
They claim to live in willful poverty, chastity and obedience.
却富甲一方
Yet they mass possessions.
并享有法外制权
And put themselves outside the law,
他们是宗教王公
They are religion princes.
即便这与我们无关
*Yet but out our responsibilities.*
这难道就是所谓的甘守清贫？
And what is willful poverty anyway?
至于说到服从 上帝作证
And that's for obedience, God help us.
如果他们连按照上帝诫令
How can they be obedient.
应该服从其一切之最高统治者都不服从
when they disobliged their sovereign Lord.
服从又何从谈起
whom by God's commandments they ought to obey in all things.
我们当然不能把这些人视作虔诚的修道人
We should not think of these men as good religious men.
因为好修道人会履行其抛弃世间财富之诺言
who forsake all earthly possessions as they claim.
倒不如说他们更像些闲人跟混混
But rather as idle and sturdy vagabonds.
我欣赏你 阿斯克先生
I like you Mr.Aske.
你或许被某些事所误导 但是
You're maybe misguiding certain matters, yes but,
你的错误就在于诚实
your mistakes are honest.
我知道 在内心深处 你最忠诚
I know that in your heart your are the most loyal of all men.
我无比热爱尊敬您 国王陛下
I love and respect Your Majesty, above all things.
从未企图冒犯您
I would never seek to offend you.
陛下 加莱的使者到了
Majesty, the bellman from Calais is here.
- 陛下 - 先生 让我看看
- Majesty. - Monsieur. Let me see.
- 陛下 - 鹌鹑蛋 弗兰西斯爵士 是鹌鹑蛋
- Majesty. - quail eggs, Sir Francis, quail eggs,
是送给王后的 先生
To feed the queen. Monsieur.